Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
Tale of Naruto the Hero
Team Jiraiya
《綱手 : 異教のマントを
羽織った男が➡
When the man in the strange cloak,
己が腹部に鋭く尖った
金属の棒を突き立てると➡
impaled himself with
his pointed metal weapon,
ナルトは同じ個所に 焼けるような
痛みを感じるのだった》
Naruto felt an excruciating pain…
in the same area of his own body.
((ナルト : クッ…。
(飛段)俺の呪いから
逃げられると思うな。
Don't think you can
escape my curse!
忍の世界は呪われてんだ。
諦めな！
The shinobi world is cursed!
Get over it!
うぅ…。
クハハハ。
なっ！ 分身だと。
What? A Clone?
う ず ま き… ナルト連弾！
Na… Ru… To…
Uzumaki Barrage!
見たか！ うずまきナルト連弾だ。
Did you see that?
It's my Naruto Uzumaki Barrage!
(サスケ)フッ 獅子連弾のモノマネか。
An imitation of my Lions Barrage.
なんだと～！
(サクラ)ケンカしてる場合？
What did you say?
This is not the time to be arguing.
あぁ そうだった。
Oh yeah, that's right…
カカシ先生はどこだ。
Where's Kakashi Sensei?
さあな。 俺たちは雇われて
実験を手伝ってるだけさ。
Who knows?
We were merely hired to help
with the experiment.
実験？
Experiment?
ああ 呪われた忍世界に
希望なんてない➡
Yeah…
To prove that there's no hope
in a cursed shinobi world.
ってことを証明するためのな。
めんどくせえから 手っ取り早く➡
It's a pain…
so I figured I'd give you
the answer real quick, but…
答えを出してやろうと
思ったんだがよ。
え？
どうやら➡
What?
I don't think he's the kind of
opponent you can handle.
お前の手に負える相手じゃ
なさそうだな。
この…。
Why you!
(弥彦)あいや しばらく！
Hey there, long time no see!
我ら妙木山 蝦蟇の精霊仙素道人➡
Trained by the Great Toad Spirit
of Mount Myoboku,
通称 ガマ仙人に鍛えられし➡
also known as the Toad Sage…
雨隠れの徒 三人！ その名も➡
…we are the trio from the Hidden Rain
チーム・ジライヤと見知りおけ。
known as Team Jiraiya,
remember that
and let our presence be known!
(いの)チ チーム…。
(チョウジ)ジライヤ？
T-Team…
Jiraiya?
(シカマル)ジライヤって
まさか伝説の三忍の…。
Jiraiya?
Are you talking about one
of the Legendary Sannin?
(いの)あ あの クールでかっこよくて
流し目がたまらなくて➡
The one who's cool and suave,
with that irresistible
sidelong glance
見つめられると１秒で女の子が
失神しちゃうって噂の!?
that makes a girl fall madly
in love in a second?
(チョウジ)それに
木ノ葉男子全員の憧れの➡
Also the one who's admired by
every guy in the Hidden Leaf
(師匠にしたいランキング１位のあの？))
and who ranks at the top of
the most desired master list?
《なんだ これは。
What the hell is this?!
自来也め
自分のことを美化しすぎだ》
Jiraiya's too full of himself!
((チーム・ジライヤ…。
ま ほんとのところ➡
Team Jiraiya…
Actually, we're called
the "Akatsuki"
暁なんつう いまいちピンとこねえ
名前で呼ばれちゃいるが➡
which isn't too catchy
or cool at all…
俺たち３人は チーム・ジライヤで
お目通り願うぜ。
But just remember the three of us
as Team Jiraiya.
自来也の弟子ってことかよ。
So you're Jiraiya's pupils?
木ノ葉のもんじゃなきゃ➡
Are you implying that only guys
from the Hidden Leaf
自来也先生の教えは受けられない。
そう言いたいのか？
can train under Jiraiya Sensei?
べ 別に そんなこと…。
What? I didn't mean it that way!
(弥彦)気に入らないんだよ
その木ノ葉面。
It really rubs me the wrong way…
When you imply that
we're not shinobi
五大国 五大隠れ里じゃなきゃ
忍にあらずってか？
since we're not from
the Hidden Leaf
and the Five Great Nations
and the Five Hidden Villages?
だから そんなこと言ってねえよ。
Like I said…I didn't say that!
ちっぽけだがよ
雨隠れの俺たちも➡
We're not a big, fancy village…
but guys like us
from the Hidden Rain
どっこい生きてるってことを
あいや 見知りおけってんだよ！
are just as good as you, got it?
Remember that and
let our presence be known!
今まで ずっと ずっとだ。
All this time, the Hidden Leaf,
Stone, Sand, and Cloud
木ノ葉 岩 砂 雲。
気分次第で
お前たちは戦争をおっぱじめ➡
have waged war whenever
they felt like it…
間に挟まれた俺たちは
行き場なく➡
And we got stuck in the middle
with nowhere to go…
ふるさとの大地は
土足で踏みにじられ➡
our homeland got ravaged
and destroyed…
それでもお前らは
俺たちの悔しさに歪んだ顔を➡
All the while, you could care less
about our suffering!
かえりみもしない。
(長門)風遁 烈風掌。
Wind Style! Gale Palm!
うわっ。
But we'll rise up.
だが 俺たちは立ち上がる。
悔しくても顔は歪めねえ。
And we won't let our bitterness
hold us back.
行き場がなくても突き進む。
We'll move forward even
if we have no place to go.
チーム・ジライヤは自由を目指す。
Liberty is Team Jiraiya's goal!
やりたいようにやり返す。
And we'll turn the tables
on you all!
やりたいようにやって
アスマたちを連れ去ったというのか。
And that's why you took
Asuma and the others?!
あんたの渾身のスピーチ それなりに
わからないでもねえが➡
Your passionate speech just now…
I understand where
you're coming from.
アスマを… 木ノ葉の仲間を
さらわれた身じゃ➡
But I don't understand
why you would capture Asuma
いまいち頭に入ってこねえんだよ。
and my comrades
from the Hidden Leaf…
木ノ葉 木ノ葉 木ノ葉
世界は木ノ葉で舞い踊るってか？
The Leaf, The Leaf, The Leaf!
Does the world revolve
around the Hidden Leaf?
冗談じゃねえんだよ！
Give me a break!
こっちだって冗談じゃねえ！
Seriously, give me a break!
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
このっ！ 神からの使徒を
足蹴にしやがって！
Why you—!
You dare to kick
an apostle of god?!
呪われやがれ！
Curse you!
キャーッ！
これは 何だってばよ！
What the hell is this?!
《火遁！ 豪火球の術！》
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
サクラちゃん 大丈夫か!?
Are you okay, Sakura?
Thank you Sasuke!
サスケ君！ ありがとう！
え～っ!?
Whaaat?!
フン… この様子じゃ 他の班も➡
Judging by this,
there's no doubt the other teams
are in the same predicament.
俺たちと同じような目に
あってると思って間違いない。
そうね… どうする？
You're right…so what do we do?
早いところ
合流したほうがよさそうだな。
The sooner we join up with them,
the better.
何か文句あるか？
Any objections?
別に。
N-No…
何なの？
What's going on?
変だよ…
行きたい方向に行けない。
This is weird. We can't go
in the direction we want to.
もしかして
誘導されてるのか？ 俺たち。
It's possible
we're being led astray!
They're not coming after us…
(いの)追ってこない…。
なんで あんなタイミングで
割り込んでくんだよ！
Why did you cut in like that?
I could've offered those kids as
a sacrifice to Lord Jashin,
行きがけの駄賃に ガキどもも
ジャシン様の生け贄にできたのによ。
while I was at it!
It's because we're not
under contract for that
(角都)契約にもない余計なことで
ドジ踏みそうだったからな。
and you were about to mess up.
俺たちの仕事は
班長クラスをとらえるところまでだ。
Our job is simply to capture
team captain-level guys.
We won't earn money
just killing brats.
小僧たちを殺したって
カネにはならない。
世の中カネだけじゃ
ねえだろうが！
The world doesn't revolve
around money.
楽しみもなきゃ
生きてる価値なんかねえっつうの。
What's the use of living
if you can't enjoy life?!
That's a luxury we can't afford.
贅沢は言えない。
Every action we take
has a priority.
どんな活動にだって
先立つものが必要だ。
チェッ！ 世知辛い話だぜ。
That's pretty harsh.
ほらよ。
なっ なんだよ？
Here you go.
What?
そいつは任せた。
You take care of this one.
I'm going to round up the rest
of the captains we've hidden.
隠してある他の班長どもを
回収してくる。
あっ おい！
Hey!
チェッ…。
(赤丸)ワン ワン！
(キバ)ああ 赤丸。
Oh, Akamaru
Yeah, it reeks here with the scent
of Shikamaru and the others.
確かに シカマルたちのニオイが
プンプンしやがる。
他にもニオイが… ３人だ。
I picked up the scent
of three guys.
(ヒナタ)つい今しがたまで
ここで戦闘があったみたい。
It seems like there was fighting
here until just moments ago.
(シノ)戦いながら
移動していったことがわかる。
They moved as they were fighting…
I can tell because…
なぜなら… 彼らは
自分たちの移動した跡を➡
…they left telltale signs
of their movements.
残していってくれたからだ。
Shikamaru and his team are okay…
シカマルたちは無事だ。
血のニオイはしてねえからな。
I don't smell any blood.
ワン… ワン！
Let's hurry after them.
急いで追いかけましょ。
A village…
(いの)集落よ…。
But don't you think
something's not right?
(チョウジ)でも なんか
様子がおかしくない？
(いの)これだけの街なのに➡
Not one sign of anyone in
a settlement this large…
人の気配が
まるでしないじゃない。
It seems they wanted
to lure us here.
あいつら 俺たちをこの集落に
誘導したかったらしいな。
どうする？
ここで 紅班を待つ？
What do we do?
Wait for Team Kurenai here?
ああ… さっきのやつら➡
Yeah… Those guys just now
probably laid out a trap
また仕掛けをして
待ち受けてるに違いねえ。
and are just biding their time.
戦力は多いほど確実だ。
The more of us there are to fight,
the better.
敵の戦力が どれほどのものか
わからない以上➡
We don't have a clue about
the enemy's strength,
まずは 仲間との合流が先だ。
so it's better to join up
with the others first.
チェッ
なんでお前が命令してんだよ。
Why are you the one giving orders?
班長がいなくなった今➡
Our captain's gone.
次に優秀な人間が
判断を下すのが妥当だろう。
Isn't it standard procedure for
the next best-qualified person
to make the decisions?
そうよね アカデミーを
首席で卒業した サスケ君と➡
I agree…
If it's between Sasuke,
who graduated at the top of the class
from the Academy…
…and you, who came in last
in our class,
ビリッケツなのに お情けで卒業した
ナルトじゃあ ね…。
and was only allowed
to graduate out of pity…
Yeah, if your dad wasn't
the Hokage…
ああ 親父が火影でなきゃあな。
なんだと やるか！
What? Wanna fight?!
Now that would be interesting.
I'll prove who's better.
フン おもしろい。
どっちが実力が上か➡
今ここで証明してやろうか。
望むところだ。
There's nothing I'd like better!
Hey, you two!
ちょっと２人とも。
俺の前で二度と そんなこと…。
Never say that again in front of me…
気づかないのか。
え!?
You haven't sensed it yet?
Huh?!
Hey guys! You were all okay?
みんなか 無事だったんだな。
ガイの姿が見えないようだが。
I don't see Guy Sensei.
(リー)ええ ガイ先生は突然
いなくなってしまったんです。
Yes.
Guy Sensei went missing suddenly.
こちらも カカシが姿を消した。
Kakashi Sensei also disappeared.
地中に引きずり込まれたような
跡だけ残してね。
There were signs that showed
he was dragged underground…
Yes, a black rope-like organism tangled
around Sensei
(テンテン)ええ 黒い紐状の生物が
引きずり込んでいった。
and dragged him away!
Yeah! That thing attacked us too.
それよ！
私たちを襲ってきたのも。
(ネジ)敵と接触したのか？
ああ 雇われたと言ってた。
You encountered the enemy?
Yeah…
They claimed to have been hired.
なあ それより
早く助けに行って…。
Hey, let's hurry and rescue them!
Don't be in such a rush.
焦るな。
だってよ。
But—!
ガイが いなくなる直前
地面の下を流れるチャクラを見た。
I saw chakra flowing underground
just before Guy went missing.
チャクラの出どころは
だいたい つかんでいる。
We've pretty much pinpointed
the source of the chakra.
だったら！
Then…
The remaining teams
should be nearby too.
残りの班も
この近くにいるはずだ。
We need to regroup
with every team first…
まずは すべての班と合流して
陣営を整えるのが先決だ。
and set up base camp.
チェッ。
Who knows what's happening
to Sensei and the others
《こんなことしてる間に➡
先生たちが
どんな目にあってるか》
while we're wasting time like this…
まずは 残りの班と合流し➡
First, we need to regroup
with the rest of the teams.
確認したいことが いくつかある。
There are a few things
I want to confirm with them.
一つは アスマ 紅が今
どうなっているか？ ってことだ。
Like the status of Asuma and Kurenai.
ガイは意識を失い… 姿を隠した。
Guy lost consciousness…
and went missing.
カカシも まったく同じだな。
The exact same thing happened
with Kakashi.
なぜ ２人は
意識をなくしたのでしょう。
Why do you think they
both lost consciousness?
そういや…
カカシ先生が消える前に➡
Come to think of it…
Kakashi Sensei was looking at
シノビアゲハを見たってばよ。
the Shinobi Ageha butterfly
before he disappeared.
おそらく シノビアゲハの鱗粉と➡
The powdery scales of
the Shinobi Ageha
地下を流れるチャクラが
相互に影響し合い…。
and the chakra flowing underground
possibly interacted with each other…
俺たちには効かず➡
There's probably a jutsu
that doesn't work on us,
上忍たちだけに効く
なんらかの術にかかったのだろう。
but affects only the jonin.
けど シノビアゲハの鱗粉には
毒性はないのよ。
But the scales of the Shinobi Ageha
aren't toxic.
術の発動条件は
俺にも わからない。
I don't know how the jutsu works.
だが さっきも言ったが
確認したいことが もう一つ。
But, like I mentioned,
there's one more thing I want to verify!
何!? それは！
What? That's—!
Lord Fourth's kunai?
四代目のクナイ!?
え… どういうことだってばよ？
What's going on?
あれ さっき サクラちゃんが
拾ったやつじゃねえの？
Isn't that the kunai that
you found earlier, Sakura?
いや… これは
ガイが落としていったものだ。
No…
This is one that Guy Sensei dropped.
上忍２人が
とっさのこととはいえ➡
Two jonin dropped the kunai
entrusted to them by Lord Fourth
at the spur of the moment…
四代目から預かった クナイを➡
落としていくとは考えづらい…。
That's hard to believe.
So if we figure that the enemy
dropped them intentionally…
敵が あえて
クナイを落としていったと考えると。
多くの術に精通した
相当な手だれか？
It's got to be someone with
considerable knowledge of various jutsu?
もしくは
四代目のクナイの秘密を知る者。
It's probably someone who knows
the secret behind Lord Fourth's kunai…
やはり 他の班との合流を
急がねばなるまい。
We'd better hurry and join up
with the other teams fast.
探索班のキバ シノ ヒナタなら➡
The tracking team of Kiba,
Shino and Hinata
かなりの確率で
居場所を特定できるはずよ。
would be able to pinpoint
the location quite accurately.
ああ おそらくな。
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
And once we know the location,
can we rescue the captains?
居場所がわかったら 助けるの？
いや…
カカシたちの状況がわかりしだい➡
No.
Once we know their situation,
we'll send word back to the village.
里と連絡を取る。
ああ。
Right. We haven't been given
the orders for a rescue.
俺たちに 救助命令は出ていない。
《また 掟かよ。
Sticking to the rules again?!
里からの救援なんか
待ってられっか！
We don't have time to wait for
reinforcements from the village!
誰が何てったって
俺は助けにいく！》
I don't care what anyone says.
I'm gonna rescue them.
Mmm… I smell food.
う～ん 何か
食べ物のニオイがするよ。
ねぇ 偵察もかねて
集落の中を探しちゃダメかな？
How about doing some search
and reconnaissance inside the village?
ダメに決まってるでしょ！
Are you kidding?
That's just looking for trouble.
そんな 火事場泥棒みたいな
真似は…。
やっぱり。
シッ。 見ろ。
I guess you're right…
Shh! Look!
Let's follow.
追ってみよう。
(アシタバ)さぁ コミチ
急いでケンタを連れていくよ。
Now Komichi…
Let's hurry and get Kenta.
Fighting's going to start soon right?
(コミチ)戦いが始まるんでしょ？
火が出たら ケンタが死んじゃう。
If there's a fire, Kenta will die.
(アシタバ)だったら なんでケンタを
置いてきちゃったんだよ。
Then why'd you leave Kenta?
Well, because—!
だって…。
よかった まだ燃えてないよ！
Thank goodness!
It hasn't burned down yet!
ケンタ ごめんよ。
もう絶対 離さないからね！
Kenta! I'm sorry!
I'll never leave you again!
We were just like them
back in the day.
あの頃の俺たちと同じだ。
Caught up in other nations' wars…
他国の戦争にさらされて
怯え 逃げて…。
Running scared…
(小南)作戦のために 村の人たちに
ケガさせちゃいけないから➡
We didn't want any villagers to
get hurt from our strategy…
みんなに
出てってもらったけど…。
So we told them all to evacuate…
Damn it…
クソッ… 今度は俺たちが➡
Now we're no different from the Hidden Leaf
and the Sand from back then…
あの頃の木ノ葉や
砂のようじゃねえかよ！
コミチ 早くして！
Komichi! Hurry up!
We have to run away before
the fighting starts.
逃げないと
戦いが始まっちゃうよ！
待って お兄ちゃん！
Wait, big brother!
Hey… Are you kids from this village?
なぁ お前らこの村の子か？
ねぇ教えて どうして
他の人たちはいないの？
Please tell us.
Where's everyone else?
(２人)うぅ…。
ああ そんなに怖がらないで。
You don't have to be scared.
We're not scary people.
お姉さんたち
怪しい者じゃないから。
Run away, Nagato!
((逃げろ！ 長門！
逃げるんだ！ 早く！
Hurry! Get away!
あ… あぁっ。
Damn it!
(クソッ！))
All right then…
なあ じゃあさ 俺たちみたいに
男２人に 女の子１人の➡
Have you seen a group of
two guys and a girl…just like us?
３人組見なかったかな？
(２人)うぅ…。
Yahiko…!
弥彦！
Nagato…!
長門！
うわぁ～！
(２人)うわぁ～！
(長門)うわぁ～！
うわぁ～！
長門！
Nagato!
Komichi!
コミチ！
あの子たちが…。
まずい！
Those kids are—!
This is bad!
そんな 僕は…。
No way… Did I…?
(２人)わ～っ！
うわっ。
ぐっ。
何だ？ あれは。
What was that?
村の中のようだな。
敵か？
It's coming from inside the village.
Is it the enemy?
Is there a team fighting over there?
どこかの班が
やり合っているというのか。
村でいったい
何が起きてるんだってばよ。
ワン ワン！
あの方角は…。
地図にある目的地の村。
シカマルたちのニオイも あっちからだ。
うむ すぐ向かうべきだろう。
なぜなら あの土煙は
何か大きな異変が➡
起こっていることを
示しているからだ。
何してんだ？ 急げ！
(シノ)ま 待て。
人の話は 最後まで聞くべきだ
なぜなら…。
おいっ 待て！
まずいよ。
あの子たち 助けなくちゃ。
待てよ。
(２人)えっ？
ダメだ 行くな。
(いの)どうして？
(チョウジ)シカマル…。
< きょうから16代目>
♪～
≫豆助
きょうは今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ？
< その小鉢とは？>